<resources>
    <string name="app_name">McqCardView</string>
    <string name="sample_text">Sample Text</string>

    <!-- All Cricketer Name -->
    <string-array name="tropic_name">
        <item>Bangla </item>
        <item>English </item>
        <item>Math </item>
        <item>ICT </item>

    </string-array>
    <string-array name="bangla_topics">
        <item>বাংলা প্রথম পত্র  </item>
        <item>বাংলা ২য় পত্র</item>

    </string-array>



    <!-- All Cricketer Image -->
    <integer-array name="tropics_image">
        <item>@drawable/bangla</item>
        <item>@drawable/english_logo</item>
        <item>@drawable/math_logo</item>
        <item>@drawable/ict</item>

    </integer-array>



   <!-- //Bangla
-->


    <string name="bangla_1st">

        ১.চুরি করার প্রয়োজন নেই বলে কারা চুরি করেনা? \n
উত্তর: সাধুরা\n

২.উদ্দিপকের শফিক ‘অপরিচিতা’ গল্পের কোন চরিত্রের প্রতিনিধি\n

উত্তর: হরিশ \n

৩.কোন কারণে উদ্দিপকের আদিব ও ‘অপরিচিতা’ গল্পের অনুপম সাদৃশ্যপূর্ণ? \n

উত্তর: (গ) ii ও iii
৪.”গ্রামের ছেলে গ্রামে বাস করবে।”______ ‘আহ্বান’ গল্পের এই বাক্যে প্রকাশ পেয়েছে গ্রামের প্রতি/উপর____ \n

উত্তর: (গ) ভালোবাসা\n

৫.’মহাজাগতিক কিউরেটর’ গল্পে প্রাণের শুরু হয়েছে কোনটি থেকে?\n
উত্তর: (ঘ) ভাইরাস\n

৬.”স্বচক্ষে দেখেছ রক্ষঃশ্রেষ্ঠ, পরাক্রম দাসের!”_______ \n
নিজেকে দাস বলার পিছনে মেঘনাদের কোন মনোভাবটি ক্রিয়াশীল?\n

উত্তর: (গ) অহমিকা\n
৭.’লোক লোকান্তর’ কবিতায় “আহত কবির গান”______ পঙক্তিটিতে কবি আহত কেন?\n

উত্তর: (গ) স্বপ্ন ও বাস্তবতার টানাপোড়নে\n

৮.আমার পথ প্রবন্ধ ও উদ্দিপকে উল্লিখিত কোন অভিন্ন কারণে শম্ভু মামুনের বাড়িতে যাওয়া থেকে বিরত থাকে?\n

উত্তর: (ক) ধর্মীয় গোঁড়ামি\n
৯.উদ্দিপকের শম্ভুর সাথে ‘আমার পথ’ প্রবন্ধের লেখকের স্বাতন্ত্র্য কীসে?\n
উত্তর: (গ) সংস্কৃতিতে\n

১০.কোন নদীর কাজল বুকে পালিতে গলিত হেম?\n

উত্তর: (গ) সুরমা\n
১১.চাবুকের বাড়ির দিকে নুরুল হুদার আর মনোযোগ দেওয়া হয়ে ওঠেনা কেন?\n

উত্তর: (গ) মুক্তিযুদ্ধাদের সম্পর্কে গভীর ভাবনায়\n

১২.উদ্দীপকের মুন্না ‘তাহারেই পড়ে মনে’ কবিতার কোন চরিত্রের কথা মনে করিয়ে দেয়?\n

উত্তর: (ক) কবি\n
১৩.উদ্দীপকে ও ‘তাহারেই পড়ে মনে’ কবিতায় যুগপৎভাবে ফুঠে উঠেছে____\n

উত্তর: (ঘ) i,iiও iii\n

১৪.”কেন এই পন্ডশ্রম, মগজে হানিছ শূল।” ______ কবি কেন এমন উক্তি করেছেন?\n
উত্তর: (খ) বিভিন্ন ধর্মগ্রন্থ মুখস্থ করায়\n

১৫.সিরাজউদ্দৌলা প্রজাসাধারণের কাছে নিজেকে অপরাধী মনে করার অন্তর্নিহিত কারণ, তিনি____\n

উত্তর: (ক) প্রজাদের সুখ-স্বাচ্ছন্দ্যের বিধান করতে পারে নি\n

১৬.’ঐকতান’ কবিতার কবি অক্ষয় উৎসাহে কী পড়েন?\n

উত্তর: (গ) ভ্রমণবৃত্তান্ত\n

১৭.’লালসালু’ উপন্যাসে কোচবিদ্ধ হয়ে নিহত হয় কে?\n

উত্তর: (গ) ছমিরুদ্দিন\n

১৮.’আঠারো বছর বয়স’ কবিতায় উল্লিখিত আঠারো বছর বয়সের কোন বৈশিষ্ট্যটি উদ্দিপকে ফুটে উঠেছে?\n

উত্তর: (ক) আত্মপ্রত্যয়\n

১৯.নিচের কোন চরণে উক্ত বৈশিষ্ট্যটি প্রকাশ পেয়েছে?\n
উত্তর: (ঘ) এ বয়সে তাই নেই কোন সংশয়\n
২০.নুসরত শাহের আশরাফপুর শিলালিপি কোন হরফে লেখা?\n
উত্তর: (গ) তুঘরা\n

২১.মোতাহের হোসেন চৌধুরী বৃক্ষের জীবনে কোন দুটি জিনিস উপলব্ধি করার পক্ষপাতী?\n

উত্তর: (ঘ) স্থৈর্য ও নীরবতা\n
২২.উদ্দীপকের সৌদামিনীর স্বামীর মধ্যে “লালসালু” উপন্যাসের কোন চরিত্রের মানসিকতা বিদ্যমান?\n

উত্তর: (গ) মজিদের\n

২৩.উদ্দীপকে এবং লালসালু উপন্যাসে আমাদের সমাজের কোন অসঙ্গতি বিদ্যমান?\n

উত্তর: (খ) বহুবিবাহ\n

২৪.”দারোগাবাবু এসে বসে আছেন বাবুর সাথে ।” ‘মাসিপিসি’ গল্পের এ বাক্যে প্রকাশ পায়____\n

উত্তর: (গ) iiও iii\n
২৫.’বায়ান্নর দিনগুলো’ রচনার কথকের সত্তায় কী লক্ষ্য করা যায়?\n

উত্তর: (ক) দৃঢ়চেতা মনোভাব\n
২৬.’ফ্রেবুয়ারী ১৯৬৯’ কবিতার লক্ষনীয় বিষয়___\n

উত্তর: (ঘ) i,iiও iii\n

২৭.’এই পৃথিবীতে এক স্থানে আছে’ কবিতায় ধানের গন্ধের মতো অস্ফুট কে?\n

উত্তর: (গ) লক্ষ্মীপেঁচা\n
২৮.উদ্দীপকের কালামের সাথে ‘সিরাজউদ্দৌলা’ নাটকের কোন চরিত্রকে তুলনা করা যায়?\n

উত্তর: (গ) সাঁফ্রে\n
২৯.এরূপ তুলনার কারণ, উভয়েই____\n

উত্তর: (ঘ) i,iiও iii\n

৩০.’সেই অস্ত্র’ কবিতায় কবির কাঙ্ক্ষিত অস্ত্র উত্তোলিত হলে কী খাঁ খাঁ করবে না?\n

উত্তর: (খ) গৃহস্থালি\n


    </string>


    <string name="bangla_2nd">



    </string>









































<!--ICT
-->
    <string name="ict">

        201. Which of these classes are used by character streams output operations ?\n
        a) ReadStream\n
        b) Writer \n
        c) InputStream \n
        d) InputOutputStream\n\n
    Correct : b) Writer\n\n

        202. How to store heavy structured data in android ?\n
a) Shared Preferences\n
        b) Cursor \n
        c) SQlite database\n
        d) Not possible\n\n
Correct : c) SQlite database\n\n


203. What are the wake locks available in android ?\n
        a) PARTIAL_WAKE_LOCK\n
        b) SCREEN_DIM_WAKE_LOCK\n
        c) SCREEN_BRIGHT_WAKE_LOCK \n
        d) FULL_WAKE_LOCK\n\n
Correct : d) FULL_WAKE_LOCK\n\n

204. What are the functionalities in asyncTask in android ?\n
a) onPostExecution()\n b) onProgressUpdate()\n
c) onPreExecution() \nd) doInBackground()\n\n
Correct : a) onPostExecution() Note: [All are correct ]\n\n
205. Fragment in Android can be found through\n
a) findByID() b) findFragmentByID() c) findFragmentByName()\n
d) FragmentManager.findFragmentByID()\n\n
Correct : d) FragmentManager.findFragmentByID()\n\n
206. Is it possible activity without UI in android ?\n\n
a) No, its not possible \nb) Yes, its possible \nc) We ca not say \nd) None of
the above\n
Correct : b) Yes, its possible \n\n

















































































































































































































        303. What is An Intent in android\n
a) a view objectt\n
        b) a messaging object \n
        c) A and B \n
        d) None of them\n\n
  Correct : b) a messaging object\n\n

304. What is An Activity\n
   a) An Activity represents a multiple screens in an app\n
   b) An Activity represents a single screen in an app\n
   c) An Activity represents exactly two screens in an app d) All of them\n\n

  Correct : b) An Activity represents a single screen in an app\n\n

305. Whan is A Service\n
   a) A Service is a component that performs operations in the background without a user interface.\n
   b) A Service is a component that performs operations in the background with a user interface.\n
   c) A Service is a component that performs operations in the foreground without a user interface.\n
   d) A Service is a component that performs operations in the foreground with a user interface.\n
  Correct : a) A Service is a component that performs operations in the background without a user interface.\n\n

306. How many types of Intent are\n
        a) 3 \n
        b) 4 \n
        c) 5\n
        d) 2\n\n
  Correct : d) 2\n\n

307. Which of the followings are intent\n
        a) Explicit intents\n
        b) Modern intents\n
        c) Implicit intents \n
        d) Call intents\n\n
  Correct : a) A and C\n\n

308. What is the name of the activity allows itself to be started by a web browser to display data referenced by a
        link, such as an image or an e-mail message.\n\n

        a) CATEGORY_BROWSABLE \n
        b) CATEGORY_LAUNCHER \n
        c) CATEGORY_BROWSE\n
        d) All of them\n\n

   Correct :a) CATEGORY_BROWSABLE\n\n

        309. What if Flags in Intent\n\n
        a) Metadat for an intent\n
        b) Metadat for an Bundle \n
        c) All of them \n
        d) one of them\n\n

    Correct : b) Metadat for an intent\n\n

        311. What is the function of ACTION_MAIN\n
        a) to indicates main entry point and does not expect any intent data\n
        b) to indicates main entry point and expects any intent data\n
        c) to indicates any entry point and expects any intent data\n
        d) to indicates any entry point and does not expect any intent data\n\n

    Correct : a) to indicates main entry point and does not expect any intent data\n\n

312. How to create a Intent launching the Browser From Your Android Applications\n
        a) Intent launchBrowser = Intent(Intent.ACTION_VIEW, uriUrl);\n
        b) Intent launchBrowser = new Intent(Intent.ACTION_VIEW, uriUrl);\n
        c) Intent = new Intent(Intent.ACTION_VIEW, uriUrl);\n
        d) All of them\n\n
    Correct : b) Intent launchBrowser = new Intent(Intent.ACTION_VIEW, uriUrl);\n\n

313. Which of the following is done to enable Web Searches\n
            a) Intent search = Intent(Intent.ACTION_WEB_SEARCH);\n
            b) Intent search = new Intent(Intent.ACTION_WEB_SEARCH);\n
            c) search = new Intent(Intent.ACTION_WEB_SEARCH); d) None of them\n\n
     Correct : b) Intent search = new Intent(Intent.ACTION_WEB_SEARCH);\n\n

314. What is the function of Layout\n
a) to defines the structure for a user interface in your app\n
b) to defines the structure for an intent in your app\n
c) to defines the structure for a storyboard in your app\n
d) None of them\n
Correct : a) to defines the structure for a user interface in your app\n\n

315. Which objects are responsible to build all elements in a layout\n
a) View and ViewGroup\n
       b) View and Scene\n
        c) View and Intent\n
        d) ViewGroup and scene\n
Correct : a) View and ViewGroup\n\n

316. a ViewGroup is\n
a) visible container\n
        b) All of them \n
        c) an invisible container\n
        d) None of them\n
Correct : c) an invisible container\n\n

317. The syntax for an ID, inside an XML tag is:\n
a) android:id="+id/my_button" \n
        b) android:id="@+id/my_button"\n
c) android:id="id/my_button"\n
        d) All of them\n
Correct : b) android:id="@+id/my_button"\n\n

318. What is the name of the APIs used to play audio and video files\n
a) CDPLayer APIs \n
        b) Player APIs \n
        c) AudioVideo APIs \n
        d) MediaPlayer APIs\n
Correct : d) MediaPlayer APIs\n\n

319. What is retrofit android ?\n
a) type safe REST Client \n
        b) Type safe client \n
        c) Client \n
        d) Session\n
Correct : a) type safe REST Client\n\n

320. What is the aim of Retrofit?\n
a) consume all services\n
        b) consume restful services \n
        c) consume web services d) none\n
Correct : b) consume restful services\n\n

321. What is by default being leaveraged by Retrofit 2?\n
a) Http \n
        b) Https \n
        ) OkHttp \n
        d) SMTP\n
Correct : c) OKHttp\n\n

322. In which, OkHttp works as a networking layer?\n
a) RetroFit\n
        b) Retro \n
        c) Retrofit 1\n
        d)Retrofit 2\n
Correct : d)Retrofit 2\n\n

323. What is Volley?\n
a) Http Library \n
        b) Https Library \n
        ) SMTP library \n
        d) retrofit library\n
Correct : a) Http Library\n\n

324. What is the advantage of volley in android?\n
a) Graphics \n
        b) Networking \n
        c) File Transfer\n
        d) Image\n
Correct : b) Networking\n\n

325. Which service is not offered by Volley?\n
a) Auto Scheduling\n
        b) Multiple Connections\n
        c) Debugging and tracing\n
        d) Auto Ordering\n
Correct : d) Auto Ordering\n\n

326. Which service is offered by Volley?\n
a) Transparent Scheduling\n
        b) Multiple Cancellation\n
        c) Debugging and tracing\n
d. Auto Ordering\n
Correct : c) Debugging and tracing\n\n

327. UI is populated by Volley using __ fill the gap\n
a) RPC type operations\n
        b) PPC type operations \n
        c) API type operations \n
        d) both a and b\n\
Corerct : a) RPC type operations\n\n

328. How a page of search is fetched by Volley ?\n
a) Structured array \n
        b) String data\n
        c) Structured Data\n
        d) none\n
Correct : c) Structured Data\n\n

329. Which uses HTTP as an underlying protocol ?\n
a) World Wide Wan \n
        b) World Wide Wap\n
        c) World Wide Web\n
        d) Email\n
Correct : c) World Wide Web\n\n

330. Which are methods of HTTP ?\n
a) POST and RETURN \n
        b) POST and GET\n
        c) GET and RETURN\n
        d) RETURN\n
Correct : b) POST and GET\n\n

331. Which method of HTTP requests data?\n
a) POST b) GET c) RETURN d) None\n
Correct : b) GET\n
332. Which method of HTTP submits data ?\n
a) POST b) GET c) RETURN d) None\n
Correct : a) POST\n\n
333. Which method of HttpURLConnection obtain a new HttpURLConnection ?\n
a) POST b) URL.openConnection c) URL.connection d) GET\n
Correct : b) URL.openConnection\n
334. What are included in URI. Request headers metadata ?\n
a) credentials b) preferred content type c) session cookies d) all of three\n
Correct : d) all of three\n\n
335. With which, instances of URLConnection class must be initialized if they contain a
request body ?\n
a) setDoOutput(true) \nb) setDoInput(true) \nc) setOutput(true) \nd) setInput(true)\n
Correct : a) setDoOutput(true)\n\n
336. Which method returns the stream which is used by URLConnection class for output ?\n
a) getOutput b) getInputStream c) getOutputStream d) getInput\n
Correct : c) getOutputStream
337. Which is not imcluded in response headers metadata ?\n
a) Response Body Content b) Response Body Type c) response body Length\n
d. Response Body History\n
Correct : d) Response Body History\n\n
338. Which are included in response headers metadata?\n
a) Response Body Content b) Response Body Type c) response body Length d) all of three\n\n
Correct : d) all of three\n\n
339. What is returned by getInputStream if response has no body ?\n
a) ouput Stream b) empty stream c) input stream d) null\n
Correct : b) empty stream\n\n
340. Which method closes the HTTPURLConnection ?\n
a) disclose b) close c) disconnect d) disrupt\n
Correct : c) disconnect\n\n
341. How many redirects HttpURLConnection will follow up to?\n
a) 5 b) 6 c) 3 d) 4\n
Correct : a) 5\n\n
342. Which method configures the connection for uploading data to a web server ?\n
a) setOutput b) setUpload c) setDoUpload d) setDoOutput\n
Correct : d) setDoOutput\n\n
343. When body length of data is known, which method should be called when uploading data ?\n
a) setFixedLengthMode b) setFixedStreamingMode c) setFixedLengthStreamingMode\n
d) setFixedMode\n
Correct : c) setFixedLengthStreamingMode\n\n
344. When body length of data is not known, which method should be called when uploading data?\n
a) setChunkedLengthMode b) setStreamingMode\n
c) setChunkedStreamingMode d) setChunkedMode\n
Correct : c) setChunkedStreamingMode\n\n
345. InputStream and OutputStream returned by HttpURLConnnection class are __?\n
a) buffered b) serialized c) unbuffered d) unserialized\n
Correct : c) unbuffered\n\n
346. What HttpURLConnection class should do for reducing latency?\n
a) use same socket for maultiple request b) use same socket for multiple response\n
c) borh a and b d) none\n
Correct : c) borh a and b\n\n
347. HTTP connections may be held __ longer than necessary.\n
a) closed b) open c) partially open d) partially closed\n
Correct : b) open\n
348. What the disconnect method of HTTP connection might return ?\n\n
a) socket b) JSON array c) Unicode Character array d) NSMUtableString\n
Correct : a) socket\n
349. What type of compression is requested by the HttpURLConnection to the servers?\n
a) gasip b) zip c) rar d) gzip\n
Correct : d) gzip\n
350. Which method of HttpURLConnection is used for data decompression?\n
a) getInputStream b) getOutputStream c) getInput d) None\n
Correct : a) getInputStream\n\n
351. How Gzip compression can be disabled ?\n
a) acceptable encodings in header b) acceptable stream c) special encodings at header d) none\n
Correct : a) acceptable encodings in header\n\n
352. What getInputStream returns when the string is exhausted?\n
a) 0 b) -1 c) 3 d) 1\n
Correct : b) -1\n\n
353. Which method returns the number of bytes transferred?\n
a) getLength b) length c) contentLength d) getContentLength\n
Correct : b) UIImage\n\n
354. Which method tests connection redirection?\n
a) getURL b) getHttp c) URI d) getURI\n
Correct : a) getURL\n\n
355. Which method triggers the receiving of response headers ?\n
a) getHeaderFields b) getInputStream c) both a and b d) none\n
Correct : c) both a and b\n\n
356. Which class includes all extensible cookie manager ?\n
a) HttpURL b) HttpURLConnection c) HttpHeader d) none\n
Correct : b) HttpURLConnection\n\n
357. Where the default cookie manager keeps all the accepted cookies?\n
a) server b) file c) cache d) memory\n
Correct : d) memory\n\n
358. What the cookies must have set to be included in headers?\n
a) domain properties b) path properties c) server properties d) both a and b\n
Correct : d) both a and b\n
359. What is the cookie version should be set for compatibility with most servers?\n
a) 11 b) 0 c) 1 d) -1\n
Correct : b) 0\n
360. Which method is used by HttpURLConnection by default?\n
a) GET b) POST c) RETURN d) None\n
Correct : a) GET\n
361. Which method causes the HttpURLConnection to use POST method ?\n
a) setDO b) setOutput c) setDoOutput d) set\n
Correct : c) setDoOutput\n
362. Which method is used to use a proxy?\n
a) URL.openConnection(Proxy) b) URL.Connection(Proxy) c) URL.open(Proxy)\n
d) URL.(Proxy)\n
Correct : a) URL.openConnection(Proxy)\n
363. Which version of android includes a response cache?\n
a) Android 1 b) Android 2 c) Android 4 d) Android 3.2\n
Correct : c) Android 4\n
364. With what type of servers, new instances of cookies work?\n
a) that support RFC 2965 cookies b) that support RFC 2695 cookies\n
c) that support RFC 2665 cookies d) both a and b\n
Correct : a) that support RFC 2965 cookies\n
365. What should be Implemented to define a custom cookie store?\n
a) store b) cookieServer c) cookieDepot d) CookieStore\n
Correct : d) CookieStore\n\n
363. Which one is a HTTP method?\n
a) GET b) DELETE c) TRACE d) all of three\n
Correct : d) all of three\n\n
364. Which one is not a HTTP method?\n
a) HEAD b) DELETE c) TRACE d) TAIL\n
Correct : d) TAIL\n\n
365. In array handling of JSON streams which method should be called first?\n
a) beginArray b) startArray c) readArray d) array\n
Correct : a) beginArray\n\n
366. In array handling of JSON streams which method should be called to read the closing bracket ?\n
a) endArray() b) finishArray() c) end() d) Array\n
Correct : a) endArray()\n\n
367. In object handling of JSON streams which method should be called first ?\n
a) begin b) startObject c) beginObject d) object\n
Correct : c) beginObject\n
368. In object handling of JSON streams which method should be called to read the closing bracket?\n
a) end() b) finishObject c) endObj() d) endObject()\n
Correct : d) endObject()\n
369. Which method is common in both array handling and object handling of JSON streams ?\n
a) beginArray b) beginObject c) endObject d) hasNext\n
Correct : d) hasNext\n\n
370. When an unknown name is encountered, what strict parsers should do?\n
a) Continue b) Fail c) Pass d) None\n
Correct : b) Fail\n
371. Which method checks if a value is null ?\n
a) peek b) nullFinder c) read d) hasNext\n
Correct : a) peek\n
372. Which method consumes null literals ?\n
a) nextPeek b) peek c) nextNull d) none\n
Correct : c) nextNull\n
373. Which method sorks alike nextNull ?\n
a) getNull b) skipValue c) nextValue d) getNext\n
Correct : b) skipValue\n
374. How JSON reader reads numeric values ?\n
a) usual way b) as string c) both a and b d) as structure\n\n
Correct : c) both a and b\n\n
375. In which way , JSON reader permits to read string values ?\n
a) as numbers b) as array c) as structure d) none\n
Correct : a) as numbers\n
376. Which method works to read next element from JSON array ?\n
a) nextInt b) nextString c) both a and b d) none\n
Correct : c) both a and b\n
377. To minimize loss, how large numeric values should be written in JSON ?\n
a) as string b) as array c) as it is d) none\n
Correct : a) as string\n
378. To maintain precision, how large numeric values should be read in JSON?\n
a) as string b) as array c) as structure d) as ponter\n
Correct : a) as string\n
379. How many JSON streams a JSON reader should read ?\n
a) double stream b) single JSON stream c) mixed data stream d) null stream\n
Correct : b) single JSON stream\n
380. JSON reader is __. Fill the gap\n
a) thread vulnurable b) thread safe c) not threadsafe d) risky\n
Correct : c) not threadsafe\n
381. Which one helps us to perform background tasks without altering threads ?\n
a) resyncTask b) threadTask c) syncTask d) AsyncTask\n
Correct : d) AsyncTask\n
382. Which method is invoked on Uithread before any task is executed ?\n
a) onPreExecute() b) onExecute() c) onReExecute() d) onPriExecute()\n
Correct : a) onPreExecute()\n
383. How many kinds of parameters are there for Async Task ?\n
a) 2 b) 3 c) 4 d) 5\n
Correct : b) 3\n
384. What is the "Params" parameter type of Async Task ?\n
a) array b) integer c) string d) structure\n
Correct : c) string\n
385. What is the "Progress" parameter type of Async Task ?\n
a) array b) integer c) string d) void\n
Correct : d) void\n
386. What is the "Result" parameter type of Async Task ?\n
a) Bitmap b) HashMap c) String d) Void\n
Correct : a) Bitmap\n
387. Which method downloads content in Async Task ?\n
a) onProgressUpdate() b) publishProgress() c) doInBackground() d) Progress()\n
Correct : c) doInBackground()\n
388. Which method updates the percent progress in Async Task ?\n
a) onProgressUpdate() b) publishProgress() c) doInBackground() d) Progress()\n
Correct : a) onProgressUpdate()\n\n
389. Which method computes the total number of bytes in Async Task ?\n
a) onProgressUpdate() b) publishProgress() c) doInBackground() d) Progress()\n\n
Correct : c) doInBackground()\n\n
390. Who is responsible for handling messages and runables ?\n
a) thread b) handler c) compiler d) operating system\n
Correct : b) handler\n\n
391. What the "@Path" annotation in retrofit denotes for ?\n
a) variable substitution for the API endpoint b) variable path for the API endpoint\n
c) variable for the API endpoint d) path substitution for the API endpoint\n
Correct : a) variable substitution for the API endpoint\n\n
392. What the "@Query" annotation in retrofit denotes for ?\n
a) specifies the query key name b) specifies the query name\n
c) specifies the key name d) specifies the name\n
Correct : a) specifies the query key name\n
393. What the "@Body" annotation in retrofit denotes for ?\n
a) payload for call b) payload for the GET call\n
c) payload for the POST call d) payload for the POST\n
Correct : c) payload for the POST call\n\n
394. Headers can be added to a request using an Interceptor\n
a) Inceptor b) Interruptor c) Interpretor d) Interceptor\n
Correct : d) Interceptor\n\n
395. Which of the following is not an extra field in android email ?\n
a) EXTRA_TITLE b) EXTRA_TEXT c) EXTRA_SUBJECT d) EXTRA_BODY\n
Correct : d) EXTRA_BODY\n\n
396. What is SQLite ?\n
a) It is an automatically integrated with cloud service\n
b) It is a temporary file and then replacing the current document\n
c) It is an in-process which is a Zero configured, self-contained and serverless\n
d) It is a library that implements a lightweight embedded relational Database\n
Correct : c) It is an in-process which is a Zero configured,
        self-contained and serverless\n
397. What is the meaning of Self Contained ?\n
a) Self Dependencies b) External dependcies \n
        c) Self motivation d) No external dependencies\n
Correct : d) No external dependencies\n
398. What is SQLite transaction ?\n
a) UNIX process b) ACID compliant c) LINUX process d) None\n
Correct : b) ACID compliant\n\n
399. SQLite is written in\n
a) C++ b) JAVA c) ANSI C d) PHP\n
Correct : c) ANSI C\n\n
400. What does mean of DDL ?\n
a) Data Decline Language b) Data Distribution Language\n
c) Data Transfer of Distributing Language d) Data Definition Language\n
Correct : d) Data Definition Language\n\n
401. What is the command of DDL ?\n
a) INSERT b) ALTER c) SELECT d) None\n
Correct : b) ALTER\n\n
402. What is SQLiteManager ?\n
a) a database manager for SQLite database b) a database manager for SQL\n
c) It is control the all documents of database d) No one\n
Correct : a) a database manager for SQLite database\n\n
403. What does the mean Of DQL ?\n
a) Data Query Language b) Data Qualification Language\n
c) Data Manipulate Language d) none\n
Correct : a) Data Query Language\n\n
404. What is the command for DQL ?\n
a) UPDATE b) DELETE c) VIEW d) SELECT\n
Correct : d) SELECT\n\n
405. Which of the following command is “DROP” ?\n
a) DQL b) DDL c) DML d)none\n
Correct : b) DDL\n\n
406. Which of the following meaning is DML?\n
a) Data Manipulate Language b) Data Manipulation Language\n
c) Data Device Manipulation Language d) Data Magnification language\n
Correct : b) Data Manipulation Language\n
<!--407. " <standard_prefix>://<authority>/<data_path>/<id>
What you will write in place of <standard_prefix>?"
a) Content b) Object c) ContentProvider d) No one
Correct : a) Content-->
408. " Choose the correct option according to the given option.\n
Statement 1: A content provider behaves very much like a database — you
        can query it, edit its content, as well as add or delete content.\n
Statement 2: Content providers let you centralize content in one place and have
        many different applications access it as needed.\n
Statement 3: A content provider does not provide the facility to centralize content. "\n
a) Option 1 is correct. b) Option 2 is correct.\n
c) Option 1and 2 is correct. d) Option 2 and 3 is correct\n
Correct : c) Option 1and 2 is correct.\n
409. Which of the following is the meaning of “CRUD” ?\n
a) create, retrieve, update, and drop
        \n b) create, retrieve, update, and delete\n
c) create, return, unite, and delete d)none\n
Correct : b) create, retrieve, update, and delete\n\n
410. " If you want to share the data from one application to other applications,
which of the following you will use? "v
a) SQLiteDatabases b) Internal Storage
        \nc) Content Provider d) None of the above\n
Correct : c) Content Provider\n\n
411. To share data across packages in Android which one you will prefer ?\n
a) Shared Preference b) Content Provider c) Data provider d) None of the above\n
Correct : b) Content Provider\n\n
412. Identifies data in a provider-\n
a) Content provider b) Data Provider c) Content URI d) Shared Preference\n
Correct : c) Content URI\n\n
413. Which of the following statement is True ?\n
a) TheContentResolver can then dispatch the query arguments to the correct provider\n
b) The ContentProvider uses the path part of the
        content URI to choose the table to access.\n
c) a and b is true d) none\n
Correct : c) a and b is true\n
414. For Creating your own content provider which class you will prefer ?\n
a) Conten b) Content Provider c) Object d) None of the above\n
Correct : b) Content Provider\n
415. How many frequency of Applet ?\n
a) 220 b) 225 c) 250 d) 255\n
Correct : b) 225\n
416. What is the uses of cursor loader ?\n
a) A callback interface you must implement b) The base class for all loaders\n
c) An implementation that uses an AsyncTask to do its work\n
d) A subclass of AsyncTask Loader for accessing ContentProvider Data\n
Correct : d) A subclass of AsyncTask Loader for accessing ContentProvider Data\n\n
417. What is/are storage option available in android ?\n
a) SharedPreference b) SQLiteDatabase
        \nc) ContentProvider d) All of the above\n
Correct : d) All of the above\n
418. What is Loader?\n
a) Loading data a content provider or other data
        \nsource for display in an FragmentActivity or Fragment
b) Changing and encapsulating a value\n
c) Converting a group of related object that can be stored
        and transferred d) None of the above\n
Correct : a) Loading data a content provider or other data
        source for display in an FragmentActivity or Fragment\n\n
419. Why does loader run on separate thread ?\n
a) To prevent from a dangerous software b) To prevent janky or unresponsive UI\n
c) Option b is false d) Option a is true\n
Correct : b) To prevent janky or unresponsive UI\n\n
420. How does the Loaders simplify a thread management ?\n
a) By providing receiver methods when event occur\n
b) By providing callback methods when event occur\n
c) By providing calling process when event occur d) All of the above\n
Correct : b) By providing callback methods when event occur\n\n
421. What does we do to prevent duplicate queries ?\n
a) Loaders persist a callback method \n
        b) Loaders persist to prevent janky or unresponsive UI\n
c) Loaders persist and cache result across configuration changes \n
        d) Which of the following\n
Correct : b) Loaders persist to prevent janky or unresponsive UI\n\n
422. Which of the following statement is true ?\n
a) Loading data a content provider or other data source for
        display in an FragmentActivity or Fragment\n
b) Loaders can implement an observer to mon\n
c) Option 1 is false b) Option 2 is false\n
Correct : a) Loading data a content provider or other data
        source for display in an FragmentActivity or Fragment\n\n
423. Characteristics of the Loaders ?\n
a) They are available to every Activity and Fragment\n
        b) They provide asynchronous loading of data\n
c) They monitor the source of their data and deliver new
        result when the content changes\n
d) All of the above\n
Correct : d) All of the above\n\n
424. What is cloud storage ?\n
a) A powerful, simple and cost-effective object storage service built for Google scale.\n
b) It is a monitor which is the source of their data a
        nd deliver the content changes\n
c) Provides a useful storage buffer which that c
        ontains of a file may be read and write\n
d) None of the mentioned\n
Correct : a) A powerful, simple and cost-effective
        object storage service built for Google scale.\n\n
425. What to use Google security to file uploads and downloads for your Firebase apps ?\n
a) Security key b) Firebase SDKs c) Software d) a and b\n
Correct : b) Firebase SDKs\n\n
426. What will you use to store images, audio,
        video, or other user-generated content ?\n
a) SDK b) Storage device c) Local storage d) All of the above\n
Correct : a) SDK\n\n
427. What will use to access the same files on the server ?\n
a) Local storage b) Google cloud storage c) Sandbox d) Local Driver\n
Correct : b) Google cloud storage\n\n
428. What is SDK ?\n
a) Software Development key b) Software Development kitten\n
c) Software Development kit d) Software Development ket\n
Correct : c) Software Development kit\n
429. The Firebase Real-time database is a-\n
a) SDK b) Cloud storage c) Cloud hosted database d) b and c\n
Correct : c) Cloud hosted database\n\n
430. What is Fairbase Real-time database?\n
a) A powerful , simple and cost –effective object
        storage service built for Google scale\n
b) A content provider or other data source for display
        in an Fragment Activity or fragment\n
c) Is synced across all clients in realtime and remains available
        when your app goes offline\n
d) Is synced across all clients in realtime and remains
        available when your app goes offline and online\n
Correct : c) Is synced across all clients in rea
        ltime and remains available when your app goes offline\n\n
431. How we can store firebase ?\n
a) DDL b) SSD c) SDK d) JSON\n
Correct : d) JSON\n\n
432. The Realtime Database provides\n
a) Flexible b) Hard c) Simple d) None\n
Correct : a) Flexible\n\n
433. The Realtime Database example is\n
a) Dynamic database b) MySql c) NoSQL d) Oracle\n
Correct : c) NoSQL\n\n
434. “JSON” stands for\n
a) JavaScript Object Notation b) JavaScript Oriented Notation\n
c) Option 1 is false d) a and b is true\n
Correct : a) JavaScript Object Notation\n\n
435. Firebase Authentication provides-\n
a) Backend services, easy to use SDKs and readymade UI liberies to
        authenticate users to your app\n
b) An implementation that uses an Asynctask to do its work\n
c) that makes sign in easy for your users using their Google account \n
        d) None of the above\n
Correct : a) Backend services, easy to use SDKs and
        readymade UI liberies to authenticate\n\n
436. FCM stands for\n
a) Firebase Control Machine b) Firebase Cloud Machine\n
c) Firebase Cloud Messaging d) Fairbase Cloud Machine\n
Correct : c) Firebase Cloud Messaging\n\n
437. What is FCM ?\n
a) a free app measurement solution that provides insight on app usage\n
b) is making sign in easy for your users using their google account\n
c) is a monetize your mobile app through in-app advertising\n
d) is a cross –platform messaging solution that lets you
        reliably deliver messages at no cost\n
Correct : d) is a cross –platform messaging solution that
        lets you reliably deliver messages at no cost\n\n
438. Which one is use of sending notification
        messages to drive user re-engagement and retention ?\n
a) FRM b) FMC c) FCM d) JSON\n
Correct : c) FCM\n\n
439. What is Google Analytics for Firebase ?\n
a) Is a free app measurement solution that provides insight
        on app usage and user engagement.\n
b) Is a trusted environment such as Cloud Functions \n
        for Firebase or an app server on which to build, target, and send messages.\n
c) Is an iOS, Android, or web (JavaScript) client app that receives messages d) none\n
Correct : a) Is a free app measurement solution that\n
        provides insight on app usage and user engagement\n\n
440. Which of the following statement is true ?\n
a) At the heart of Firebase is Google Analytics for Firebase,
        a free and unlimited analytics solution.\n
b) The Loader API lets you load data from a content
        provider or other data source for display in an FragmentActivity or Fragment.\n
c) Data is synced across all clients in realtime,
        and remains available when your app goes offline.\n
d) All of the above\n
Correct : a) At the heart of Firebase is Google Analytics for Firebase,\n
        a free and unlimited analytics solution\n\n\n
441. How many distinct events that you can define using the Firebase SDK ?\n
a) 300 events b) 400 events c) 500 events d) 600 events\n
Correct : c) 500 events\n\n
442. How does analytics work ?\n
a) help up to debug app b) Encapsulating the values\n
c) helps you understand how people use your iOS or Android app. d) None of the above\n
Correct : c) helps you understand how people use your iOS or Android app.\n
443. How many types of Google Analytics for firebase ?\n
a) 2 b) 3 c) 4 d) 5\n
Correct : a) 2\n
444. Analytics reports help-\n
a) Understand user behavior and view live usage data with real time reporting\n
b) Understand clients problem \nc) Identifying the problem easily \nd) a and b is both\n
Correct : a) Understand user behavior and view live usage data with real time reporting.
\n445. What is AdMob ?\n
a) Is Google’s advertising platform for promoting and monetizing mobile applications\n
b) Is a free app measurement solution provides insight apps usages.\n
c) Is a google ‘s platform which is moving on side from another side\n\n
d) A and B is true\n
Correct : c) Is a google ‘s platform which is moving on side from another side\n\n
446. How AdMob can be displayed ?\n
a) As audio, picture and design etc\n b) Movie, maps, poems etc\n
c) Audio, maps, poems, movie, banner ads etc \n
        d) as banner ads, interstitial ads, video ads, or native ads\n
Correct : d) as banner ads, interstitial ads, video ads, or native ads\n\n
447. Admob uses –\n
a) Mobile ads b) SDK c) Google Mobile Ads SDK. d) Video ads\n
Correct : c) Google Mobile Ads SDK.\n\n
448. Which helps app developers gain insights about their users,
        drive more in-app purchases, and maximize ad revenue.\n
a) Google Mobile Ads SDK b) DDL c) DML d) Provider\n
Correct : a) Google Mobile Ads SDK\n
449. Apps can import the Google Mobile Ads SDK with a
        Gradle dependency that points to_______________ repository\n
a) Google Mobile Ads SDK b) Google's Maven c) Google's Maven d) None\n
Correct : b) Google's Maven\n\n
450. Google Mobile Ads SDK support across-\n
a) Android b) Ios c) Game engine d) All of the above\n
Correct : d) All of the above\n
451. Which is a technical discussion regarding
        the Android Google Mobile Ads SDK in google play service\n
a) Android b) Ios c) Game engine d) All of the above\n\n
Correct : a) Android\n\n
452. What is Unity and Cocos2d-x ?\n
a) Ios b) Android c) Game engine d) Google mobile ads sdk\n\n
Correct : c) Game engine\n\n
453. Once installed on a device, each Android application lives in_________\n
a) device memory b) external memory
        \nc) security sandbox d) None of the above\n
Correct : c) security sandbox\n\n
454. What are the Direct subclasses of Activity?\n
a) Account Authenticator Activity b) Activity Group
        \nc) Fragment Activity d) All of the above\n
Correct : d) All of the above\n\n
455. When content Provider would be activated ?\n
a) Using Intent b) Using SQLite
        \nc) Using Content Resolver d) none of the above\n
Correct : c) Using ContentResolver\n
456. What is the function of AdMob ?\n
a) Monetizing mobile app b) Purchasing mobile app\n
c) Modifying mobile app d) Creating mobile app\n
Correct : a) Monetizing mobile app\n\n
457. How Ads can be displayed using AdMob ?\n
a) Banner Ads b) Video Ads b) Video Ads
        \nc) Native Ads d) All of the above\n
Correct : d) All of the above\n\n
458. What is the unique identifier of AdMob Account ?\n
a) Ad Unit Ids b) Mob Unit Ids c) Native Ids d) None of the above\n
Correct : a) Ad Unit Ids\n\n
459. What does AdMob use ?\n
a) Windows Mobile Ads SDK b) Google Mobile Ads SDK \n
        c) Both a and b d) None of the above\n
Coorect : b) Google Mobile Ads SDK\n\n
560. How Google Mobile Ads SDK helps app developers ?\n
a) Gaining insight about their users b) Driving more in app purchase\n
c) Maximizing and Revenue d) All of the above\n
Correct : d) All of the above\n\n
461. What type of information Mobile Ads SDK collect ?\n
a) Device information b) App purchase information \n
        c) Both a and b d) None of the above\n
Correct : c) Both a and b\n\n
462. How Google Mobile Ads SDK helps app developers ?\n
a) Gaining insight about their users b) Driving more in app purchase\n
c) Maximizing and Revenue d) All of the above\n
Correct : d) All of the above\n\n
463. Which uses the path part of the content uri developers ?\n
a) Content Resolver b) Content URI c) Data Dictionary d) Content Provider\n
Correct : d) Content Provider\n\n
464. What does Content Uri identifies ?\n
a) Data b) Path c) Both a and b d) None of the above\n
Correct : a) Data\n\n
465. Why projection is used ?\n
a) Retriving each column b) Retriving each row c) Selecting rows d) Selecting columns\n
Correct : b) Retriving each row\n\n
466. What does selection command specifies ?\n
a) Retriving rows b) Retriving columns c) Selecting columns d) Selecting rows\n
Correct : d) Selecting rows\n\n
467. What type of dependency is required to import an android app ?\n
a) App Building Dependency b) Gradle Dependency c) Both a and b d) None of the above\n
Correct : b) Gradle Dependency\n\n
468. What does google analytics provide for firebase ?\n
a) Driving more app in purchase b) Maximizing and Revenue\n
c) User engagement d) Retriving information\n
Correct : c) User engagement\n\n
469. What is google analytics ?\n
a) Free App Measurement Solution a) Paid App Measurement Solution\n
c) Both a and b d) None of the above\n
Correct : a) Free App Measurement Solution\n\n
470. How many features provide when you use the Firebase SDK ?\n
a) About 300 a) About 400 a) About 500\n
Correct : a) About 500\n\n
471. Which of the following features is integrated with Google Analytics ?\n
a) Mongo DB b) MS SQL Server c) Firebase d) None of the above\n
Correct : c) Firebase\n\n
472. How google analytics help you to make your app better ?\n
a) Interaction of the user b) Informing decision about app marketing\n
c) Optimizing performance d) All of the above\n
Correct : d) All of the above\n\n
473. What does FCM stands for ?\n
a) Firebase Clone Messaging b) Firebase Cloud Management\n
c) Firebase Cloud Messaging d) None of the above\n
Correct : c) Firebase Cloud Messaging\n\n
474. What does Firebase Authentication provide ?\n
a) Frontend Services b) Backend Services c) Readymade UI libraries d) Both b and c\n
Correct : d) Both b and c\n
475. What does Firebase Authentication Supports ?\n
a) Password b) Phone Number c) ID Card d) Both a and b\n
Correct : d) Both a and b\n
476. Which IDE is used for Android development ?\n
a) Eclipse b) Andoroid Studio c) Netbeans d) a and b\n
Correct : d) a and b\n\n
477. What is the name of Android version 8 ?\n
a) Nougat b) Oreo c) Marshmallow d) Kitkat\n
Correct : b) Oreo\n\n
478. What is the API level of Oreo ?\n
a) 26 b) 22 c) 25 d) 21\n
Correct : a) 26\n\n
479. Which level allows high level interaction with andoird system ?\n
a) Runtime b) Libraries c) Application Framework d) None of the above\n
Correct : c) Application Framework\n\n
480. Which language is used for native Android development ?\n
a) C# b) Java c) HTML , Javascript d) PhoneGap\n
Correct : b) Java\n\n
481. Which one is a OOP feature ?\n
a) Abstraction b) Polymorphism c) Inheritence d) All of the above\n
Correct : d) All of the above\n\n
482. What is Encapsulation ?\n
a) Everything inside an unit b) Inherit all criteria from parent\n
c) Take any relevant form d) None of the above\n
Correct : a) Everything inside an unit\n\n
483. What is abstraction ?\n
a) Everything inside an unit b) Inherit all criteria from parent\n
c) Hiding internal details d) All of the above\n
Correct : c) Hiding internal details\n\n
484. What is polymorphism ?\n
a) Everything inside an unit b) Object behaving differently in different situaltions\n
c) Hiding internal details d) Inherit all criteria from parent\n
Correct : b) Object behaving differently in different situaltions\n\n
    </string>


</resources>
